Hello programmer welcome back to today's another tutorial topic. So to this topic for here is the
Relating to the MongoDB documents. So using for the MongoDB shell. So in this session,
I can just try for the program to explore how to collect documents from the MongoDB collection
using the various data operations and the syntax. So here ensure perfectly this MongoDB
shell. So my MongoDB shell is now completely connected. So you can perfectly check for this
connection option. Okay. So now I can just go. So first of all here, the first example,
define for here the creating a single document. So you can just try for here. So now just open for
this MongoDB shell just here and then first kit, first on comment for here. This is the single
document from the collection's name is student. So first of all, I can tag for the DB that is the
collection's name. So suppose for the students. Okay. And now here, I can use for the delete on
option. So this type for the delete. So students dot then delete. Okay. So
DE. Delete this on the last on the delete one. And here, first, I can clearly define the
parenthesis and also create the example. So here, first of all, define for the name. And now here,
I can define. So now I can just use the double quotation. It is the name is zero and five. Okay.
So here this comment for a single document from the collection where the name field is zero and
five. Okay. So now I have completely defined and pressed enter. And you can see the acknowledgement
is true and the discount is one. Okay. So this MongoDB acknowledgement is successful
deletion of the document. Okay. So I hope you understand it.
Next step here, first example is done. And now we can delete for the multiple documents. Okay.
So now just here, first of all, type the DB dot the collections name.
The students dot here, I can just write this. Delete for finale. And now here, I can just create
the parenthesis and also the curly brackets. So now here, I can just add the city. So the city name
is defined. So perfectly. So now here, I can use for the city name. So now just go here. So here,
it is for the city name is Chicago. Okay. So the Chicago is defined for the city name. So now here,
the perfectly defined and in this statement, for this command is developed for the multiple
documents from my collection for the collection of students while the city field in Chicago. Okay.
And I have completely done and pressed for the enter. And you can see the acknowledgement is perfectly
cleared. And we have perfectly deleted and removed for this. So now I have perfectly used for the
two function, the delete one and delete nine. Okay. Now here, I can use for another option. So now
I can just delete the documents based on the specific conditions. Now, first of all, here, I can just
copy for. Okay. So now just type for the DB. So just go here, the DB dot then.
Students for the collections name, here, I can just again use for the delete menu. So this
delete menu function. And there are first of all, type. There's parentheses are defined for
the each column. And now here, I can use tag in the curly brackets and tag for the daughter sign
and just suppose we can define for the L and P and the L. Okay. Then create. And here, it is used
for the age is 25. Okay. So this comment will delete the documents from the collection
where each field is less than 25. Okay. So defined perfectly. And there I can just paste the
enter. You can see this acknowledgement is true. And they are this one. Okay. So you can choose for
delete for all documents from the collection. So you can just type for here. And I can just
here, you can use the copy for this data. Okay. Now here, just you can see for here and paste. And
you can choose for the delete menu. And simply paste for the parentheses and also paste for the curly
brackets. Okay. So you can just try for type this C text for the document. And now press for
the enter. And here, the among would be acknowledgement create for the successful master
deletion for all the documents from the collection. Okay. So this now, you can try and you can
perfectly try for this comment and perfectly see the result for in your display. Okay. So now
here, this is completely done. And to the station, I have perfectly tried for the delete function
in the MongoDB. Okay. So thank you for watching and happy coding.